MD. IBRAHIM ARAFAT

Contact: 282 South Kafrul, Dhaka Cantonment, Dhaka, Bangladesh arafat0112358@gmail.com

+880 1944-416535



A confident, reliable and enthusiastic professional who has vast experience of managing technically complex projects, and possesses a forward-thinking approach to the management of clients and assignments. I have the ability to deliver complex projects with a goal reach, and am able to manage the project delivery team entire life cycle, from client enquiry to invoice. Beside that I have 5 years professional experience in Software Engineering and Web Application Development.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Groovy, PHP, Action Script 3 and C++ Technologies/Libraries: JSP, Servlets, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery

Framework: Grails, Spring, Hibernate, Struts, CodeIgniter

Databases: PostgreSql, MySQL

Reporting: Jasper Report

Deployment Framework: Maven Application Server: Apache Tomcat

Development Tools: IntelliJ Idea, Sublime Text, PhpStorm

Platforms: Mac OS X, Windows 2000/7 and LINUX

Methodologies: Agile

Tools: ZIRA, PMIS, Basecamp, Salesforce, GIT

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr. Software Engineer

ServicEngine BPO

1st August 2014 – Present | Mohakahli, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Software Engineer

Athena Software Associates 1st July 2013 – 31st July 2014 | Tejgaon Industrial Area, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Software Engineer

Team Creative

1st September 2012 – 30th June 2013 | Banani, Dhaka, Bangladesh



Jr. Software Engineer

itPlorer Limited

1st October 2011 – 30th August 2012 | Mehedibag, Chittagong, Bangladesh

Projects:

Inventory Management System

Project Description: Corolla Corporation uses Inventory Management System. The main modules of this software are:

- Budget
- Procurement
- Inventory.
- Accounting.
- Quantity Survey (QS)

Technologies: Java (Groovy), Grails, Hibernate, JQuery, PostgreSQL, Jasper Report and Tomcat

Responsibilities:

- Requirement Analysis and DB design
- Designing database schema after consulting with my superior.
- Designed and implemented the client or server technologies and features.
- Performed Unit Tests.
- Specified and performed Feature Deliverables Test plans.
- SQL Query Coded on Core ERP and Jasper Report for generating Crystal Report.
- Working as a team player

Health Care Innovations Program

Project Description: "Health Care Innovations Program" is health-care program software, generally used by NGO. The main modules of this Health-Care software are:

- Operational Structure
- Benefit Package
- Member Information
- Economy Condition

Technologies: Java (Groovy), Grails, Hibernate, JQuery, PostgreSQL, Jasper Report, Tomcat

Exchange House

Project Description: "Exchange House" is remittance maintenance software used by Southeast Bank. The main modules of this MIS software are:

- Task (3 Category)
- Customer (3 Category)

Technologies: Java (Groovy), Grails, Hibernate, JQuery, PostgreSQL, Jasper Report, Tomcat

Flash Games for Team Creative (champs21.com)

Project Description: This was a web based eLearning based Flash games developing project.

Technologies and Platforms: Adobe Flash CS6, Photoshop, Windows 7 and Action Script 3

Responsibilities:

- Game logic development
- Game animation
- Performed Unit Tests.
- Game UI design

Web development for itPlorer Limited

Project Description: This was a websites and small web application development company.

Technologies and Platforms: CodeIgniter framework, PHP storm, XAMPP, Windows 7, MySQL database, PHP, HTML

Responsibilities:

- Requirement collection & analysis
- Database design & implementation
- Performed Unit Tests.
- Website & Web application development

EDUCATION

B.Sc. in Computer Science & Engineering, International Islamic University, Chittagong, Bangladesh 01/2008-03/2012 CGPA is 3.446 out of 4.00

Higher Secondary Certificate (H.S.C) in Science, B. A. F Shaheen College, Chittagong, Bangladesh 01/2004-12/2006 GPA is 3.70 out of 5.00

Secondary School Certificate (S.S.C) in Science, Nasirabad Govt. Boys High School, Chittagong, Bangladesh 01/1998-12/2004 GPA is 4.19 out of 5.00

Md. Ibrahim Arafat

E-mail: arafat0112358@gmail.com

Mobile: 01687127823